<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/monicasira/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/monicasira/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-08T15:41:55+00:00</updated><id>/monicasira/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MrS</title><subtitle>Greatness, whatever it could mean.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ruby’s Struct</title><link href="/monicasira/code/ruby/oop/2021/12/08/struct.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ruby’s Struct" /><published>2021-12-08T15:26:12+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T15:26:12+00:00</updated><id>/monicasira/code/ruby/oop/2021/12/08/struct</id><content type="html" xml:base="/monicasira/code/ruby/oop/2021/12/08/struct.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-rubys-struct-library-do&quot;&gt;What does Ruby’s struct library do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Struct can help you create a class quickly.&lt;br /&gt;
The class can be instantiated, have getter and setter methods.&lt;br /&gt;
The class can also be given a block to add more methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  class Cat
    attr_accessor :name
    
    def initialize(name=nil)
      @name = name
    end
  end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is equivalent to
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Cat = Struct.new(:name)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><category term="ruby" /><category term="oop" /><summary type="html">What does Ruby’s struct library do? Struct can help you create a class quickly. The class can be instantiated, have getter and setter methods. The class can also be given a block to add more methods.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cool ruby libraries</title><link href="/monicasira/code/ruby/libraries/2021/12/08/cool-libraries.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cool ruby libraries" /><published>2021-12-08T15:26:12+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T15:26:12+00:00</updated><id>/monicasira/code/ruby/libraries/2021/12/08/cool-libraries</id><content type="html" xml:base="/monicasira/code/ruby/libraries/2021/12/08/cool-libraries.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;new-libraries-for-me&quot;&gt;New libraries for me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;etc - operating system access, example class method: #getlogin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><category term="ruby" /><category term="libraries" /><summary type="html">New libraries for me etc - operating system access, example class method: #getlogin</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ruby’s Forwardable</title><link href="/monicasira/code/ruby/oop/2021/12/08/forwardable.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ruby’s Forwardable" /><published>2021-12-08T14:37:12+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T14:37:12+00:00</updated><id>/monicasira/code/ruby/oop/2021/12/08/forwardable</id><content type="html" xml:base="/monicasira/code/ruby/oop/2021/12/08/forwardable.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-does-rubys-forwardable-library-do&quot;&gt;What does Ruby’s forwardable library do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you find that you are using one method to call another object’s variable&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;For example: User#first_name refers to Account#first_name&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forwardable can help with de-duplicating your code.
By adding
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;require 'forwardable'&lt;/code&gt; and
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;def_delegators :account, :first_name&lt;/code&gt;
we can access user.first_name.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><category term="ruby" /><category term="oop" /><summary type="html">What does Ruby’s forwardable library do? Sometimes you find that you are using one method to call another object’s variable For example: User#first_name refers to Account#first_name</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On Tennis and Code</title><link href="/monicasira/code/tennis/2021/08/28/on-tennis-and-code.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Tennis and Code" /><published>2021-08-28T02:58:12+00:00</published><updated>2021-08-28T02:58:12+00:00</updated><id>/monicasira/code/tennis/2021/08/28/on-tennis-and-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="/monicasira/code/tennis/2021/08/28/on-tennis-and-code.html">&lt;p&gt;So recently I’ve been following tennis tournaments - Wimbledon, Olympics, Canadian Open. I played in highschool, but never followed tennis back then. Even a couple months ago, I only watched 9-10 minute clip highlights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does one get from those highlights? Sometimes it represents how the whole match went, other times it just shows the longest, exciting, remarkable shots from a tennis player. Then, from all that you see, you form an opinion of the player. She screams too much, he’s so emotional, of course she would win, how could he make that many unforced errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it fair? Maybe, maybe not. But then I watched full match of Djokovic vs. Shapovalov. Its a given the number 1 ranked player was going to win. Right? It should have been easy for me to tell. But during the first 12 games of the first set I couldn’t. Each player held serve, and Shapo was serving tremendously. Djokovic kept grinding away, chipping away, until he won the tie-breaker to take the first set. And a similar pattern took place until he won the match in 3 sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all this to say it’s not a given the number 1 player will win. It’s really my own misconception. I think I give top seeded players less credit than they deserve. At the level top 10 players are competing, the margins of strokes and shot making aren’t that big. The same margins give all players the confidence to be number 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching a full match you also see how a player’s emotion could be affected by every point. At 15-30 Player A serving, she strikes a hard forehand winner. Confidence increase. At 30-30, the two players get in a long rally, ending with Player B winning the point. Player A’s confidence slightly decreases. The next point, 30-40 results in Player A making a forehand unforced error. At every point, how can she manage to strike the ball confidently, finding a balance between precision and arrogance, to put all the negative thoughts behind and focus on the present shot? And if she loses the match, how does she find the strength to play in the next tournament, and the tournament after?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some answer that its her livelihood. All she can do is get the right feedback and keep improving. Some say she should find another job. Ultimately, she continues because she knows herself, that she is seeking the best coaches, the most feedback, and working hard towards being number 1.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="code" /><category term="tennis" /><summary type="html">So recently I’ve been following tennis tournaments - Wimbledon, Olympics, Canadian Open. I played in highschool, but never followed tennis back then. Even a couple months ago, I only watched 9-10 minute clip highlights.</summary></entry></feed>